Finding Aid for the Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr. Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr. Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0626
Biographical Timeline
1928 Born in Uniontown, PA in
1946 Graduated from Washington High School in Massillon, OH in
1947 Received his local preacher’s license in
September 29, 1947 Entered Baldwin-Wallace College in Berea, OH on
1948 Became involved in the Fellowship for Reconciliation (FOR), which advocated nonviolent resistance to racism in
1951-1952 Declared a conscientious objector, refusing to take either a student or ministerial deferment, and served 14 months in federal prison (two months before graduating from college) for failing to report for the draft during the Korean War
1952 Attended the Hartford Theological Seminary in CT in
December 1952 Graduated from Baldwin-Wallace College with a BA in Sociology in
1953-1955 Worked as a Methodist minister and teacher at Hislop College in Nagpur, India where he studied the principles of nonviolence resistance that Mahatma Gandhi and his followers had developed
1955 Attended Oberlin School of Theology in OH in
1957-1960 Attended Vanderbilt Divinity School in TN in
Served as president of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference for 14 years, the organization founded by Martin Luther King, Jr. to end racial segregation by nonviolent protest
February 1960 Organized sit-ins to stop segregation at lunch counters in downtown Nashville, TN
Expelled from Vanderbilt Divinity School on March 3, 1960, resulting in resignations of faculty members in protest and embroiled the campus and the Nashville community in a nationally reported controversy for months in the spring of 1960. A compromise was forged to stop most of the resignations and allow Lawson to complete dis degree in Nashville. Lawson instead chose to transfer to Boston University.
1960 Founded, along with Martin Luther King, Jr., the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee in
1960 Completed his Bachelor of Divinity degree at Boston University ca.
1960-1962 Pastor at Scott Chapel Methodist Church in Shelbyville, TN from
1961 Coordinated the Freedom Rides in
1962-1974 Pastor at Centenary United Methodist Church in Memphis, TN from
1965 Member of an international peace team in Southeast Asia, replacing Martin Luther King, in
1966 Coordinator of the James Meredith March in Mississippi in
1966 First president of Black Methodists for Church Renewal in
1967 Unsuccessful Campaign for Memphis Board of Education in
1967 Chair of the Strategy Committee for the Memphis Sanitation Strike ca.
April 4, 1968 Martin Luther King, Jr., assassinated in Memphis, TN on
1971 Returned to Vanderbilt on a sabbatical at the Divinity School in
1974-1989 Pastor at Holman United Methodist Church in Los Angeles, CA from
1981 Arrested for praying on the White House grounds in
Chaired Peace Sunday in Los Angeles, CA in 1982, filling the Rose Bowl with 100,000 people
1991 Hosted a weekly call-in show, ‘Lawson Live,’ where he discussed social and human rights issues affecting minority communities ca.
1999 Retired at pastor at Holman United Methodist Church in
2005 Named Vanderbilt’s Distinguished Alumnus in
Lawson’s expulsion from Vanderbilt in 1960 became a source of deep embarrassment to the university. During the 2006 graduation ceremony the university apologized for its treatment of Lawson.
2006-2007 Lawson became a Distinguished University Professor at Vanderbilt for the academic year
The papers contain a wide range of materials documenting Reverend Lawson’s life.
The papers are arranged and described in the following series:
- Education
  Washington High School
  Baldwin-Wallace College
  Hartford Theological Seminary
  Oberlin School of Theology
  Vanderbilt Divinity School
  Boston University
- Federal Prison – Conscientious Objector – Korean War
- Church Affiliations
  Turner Chapel Methodist Church – Canton, Ohio
  Hislop College – Nagpur, India
  Warren Chapel Methodist Church 10/1/56
  Scott Chapel Methodist Church – Shelbyville, Tennessee
  Centenary United Methodist Church – Memphis, Tennessee
  Holman United Methodist Church – Los Angeles, California
- Church Committees
  Ad Hoc Committee for the 1984 Olympic Games
  Black Methodist for Church Renewal
  Board of Christian Social Concerns
  Central Jurisdiction of the Methodist Church
  Citizens Advisory Committee on Student Integration
  Citizens Concerned with Improved Police Community Relations
  Commission on Religion and Race
  Committee for Nonviolent ACTION
  Committee of Southern Churchmen
  General Board of Global Ministries
  General Conference of the United Methodist Church
  General Council on Ministries
  JAPLA: Justice, Action, and Peace in Latin America
  Joint Task Force on Health and Welfare Ministries
  National Committee of Black Churchmen
  National Conference Of Negro Methodists
  National Council on Churches
  Quadrennial Emphasis of the United Methodist Church
  Southern California-Arizona Annual Conference
  United Methodist Church Renewal
  Western Jurisdictional Conference
  World Conference on Religion and Peace
  World Council of Churches
- Civil Rights
  General Subject Files
  Hospital Strike – Memphis
  Memphis Sanitation Strike
  Civil Rights Project – see audio-visual
- Assassination
  Martin Luther King, Jr. – Assassination
  James Earl Ray
- Organizations
  Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR)
  Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC)
- Book Draft
- Return to Vanderbilt University, 2006-2010
- Audio-Visual Materials
  Cassette Tapes
  Reel-to-Reel Tapes
  VHS Tapes
  Photographs
  Posters
  Scrapbooks
- Awards and Plaques
- Education
  - Washington High School in Massillon, OH 1940s – Box 28
  Newspaper clippings
  Photographs (3)
  - Baldwin-Wallace College – Box 28B
  Correspondence – incoming - 1947
  Correspondence – incoming – 1948
  Correspondence – incoming – 1949
  Correspondence – incoming – February 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – May 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – July 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – August 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – September 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – November 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – December 1950
  Correspondence – incoming – 1951
  Correspondence – incoming - 1952
  Correspondence – incoming – n.d.
  Prayer Notes - 1947
  Sermon Ideas 1947-1949
  Debate Team 1946-1947
  Young People’s Leadership Regional Training Conference 1947-1948
  Newspaper Clippings - 1947-1949
  Pamphlets – ‘The Methodist Church and War and Peace’ 1948
  Classes – Philosophy and Ethics – Spring 1949
  Dean’s List and Scholarship Award 1947-1949
  Worship Services 1948-1950
  Publications 1950-1951
  Methodist Student Loan - 1951
  Methodist Youth Assembly - May 1952
  Will – July 27, 1952
  Commencement – June 7, 1953
  Speech – ‘Alternative to Destruction’ - n.d.
  - Hartford Theological Seminary
  - Oberlin School of Theology – Box 30
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1956
  Correspondence – incoming – 1957
  Correspondence – incoming – 1958
  Engagement – Fall 1957
  International Fellowship of Reconciliation – n.d.
  Newspaper Clippings – King at Oberlin – February 1957
  Newspaper Clippings – 1957-1958
  Lexington Conference – 1957-1958
  Medical Records – 1957-1958
  Methodist Federation of Social Action – 1955-1956
  Methodist Youth Foundation – 1956
  Minutes – Student-Faculty Meeting – October 11, 1956
  Instruction for Colloquy Leaders – n.d.
  North American Faith and Order Conference – 1957
  Programs – 1956-1957
  - Oberlin School of Theology – box 29
  Courses - Education Work of Local Churches – Fall 1956
  Courses - New Testament I – Fall 1956 (2 folders)
  Courses - Church History Survey – Fall 1957
  Courses - History of Religions – Fall 1957
  Courses - Practicum – Fall 11957
  Courses - Psychology of Christian Character – Fall 1957
  Courses - A Year’s Preaching – Fall 1957
  Courses - The Christian Religion – Spring 1957
  Courses - Fundamental of Sermon Construction – Spring 1957
  Courses - New Testament 2 – Spring 1957
  Courses - Old Testament History – Spring 1957
  - Vanderbilt University Divinity School – Box 62
  Correspondence – Incoming – General - 1958
  Correspondence – Outgoing – General - 1958
  Correspondence – Incoming – General - 1959
  Correspondence – Incoming - General - 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – n.d.
  Correspondence – Incoming – February 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – March 1-14, 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – March 15-31, 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Outgoing – March 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming from Vanderbilt – 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming to Vanderbilt – 1960-1961 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – April 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – May 1960 re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – Cooperative Agencies Supporting Sit-Ins – 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – n.d. re: Sit-Ins
  Correspondence – Incoming – Highlander Folk School - 1960
  Engagements – May 1960 – Gethsemani Retreats
  Nashville Christian Leadership Conference – 1959-1960
  Nashville Christian Leadership Conference – 1961-1962
  High School Integration Consultation – May 1958
  Nashville Non-Violent Movement – n.d.
  Sit-In Notes – n.d.
  Southern Conference Education Fund – 1958
  Essay – ‘The 1960 Case of the Absent-Minded Professors’
  Newsletter –‘ CORE-LATOR’ – March 1960
  Newsletter – ‘wesley notes’ – March 7, 1960
  Newspaper – “Witness to the Light” – Civil Rights Struggle in Nashville – 1957-1964 – published February 2, 1993 by Nashville Banner Newspaper
  Pamphlet – ‘koinonia’ – May 1960
  Pamphlet – ‘Prospectus’ – March 1980
  Report – ‘A Report on Nashville’ – by Wallace Westfeldt – n.d.
  Sermon – ‘A Man Had Two Sons’ – by Will Campbell – May 1959
  National Student Christian Federation – June 1960
  - Vanderbilt University Divinity School – Box 56
  Courses – Beginning Greek – Fall 1958
  Courses – History of American Christianity
  Courses - History of Christian Doctrine – Fall 1958
  Courses – Old Testament Theology – Fall 1958
  Courses – Beginning Greek – Spring 1959
  Courses – History of Christian Doctrine – Spring 1959
  Courses – History of European Christianity – Spring 1959
  Courses – New Testament Theology – Spring 1959
  Courses – The Life and Teachings of Jesus – Summer 1959
  Courses – Pastoral Counseling – Summer 1959
  - Vanderbilt University Divinity School – Box 58
  Courses – Advanced New Testament Greek – Fall 1959
  Courses – Advanced Practice Preaching – Fall 1959
  Courses – History and Theology of Methodism – Fall 1959
  Courses – Introduction to Theology – Fall 1959
  Courses – Christian View of History – Spring 1960
  Courses – Systematic Theology – Spring 1960
  - Vanderbilt University Divinity School – Box 57
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1968
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1969
  Correspondence – Incoming - 1970
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1971
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1971
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1974
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1975
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1986
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1987
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1991
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1997
  Courses – The Black Religious Experience – Fall 1970
  Courses – Christianity and Culture – Fall 1970
  Courses – Thesis Program – Fall 1970
  Courses – Readings in Ethics – Spring 1971
  Courses – Theology and the Black Experience – Spring 1971
  Engagements – Convocation – February 14, 1969
  Engagements – Racism, Racists and Theological Education – February 11, 1971
  Engagements – National Association of Human Rights Workers – March 16, 1971
  Engagements – Martin Luther King, Jr. Lecture – February 14, 1984
  Engagements – Martin Luther King, Jr. Lecture – January 23, 1985
  Engagements – Martin Luther King, Jr. Lecture – January 21, 1987
  Engagements – Martin Luther King, Jr. Lecture – February 2, 1990
  Engagements – Panel – March 26, 1996
  Newspaper Clippings – Busing – 1971
  Newspaper Clippings – Racism and Discrimination – 1971
  Newspaper Clippings – War and Nixon – 1971
  Newspaper Clippings – Whitney M. Young, Jr. – 1971
  Newspaper Clippings – VU Lax in Racism Fight – 1980 and 1986
  Economic Withdrawal for Racial Justice – March 4, 1971
  Vanderbilt Divinity School Program – 1969-1970
  General Program – 1971
  Kelly Miller Smith Institute on the Black Church – 1985-1987
  Sermons by Vanderbilt Chaplain – 1970-1971
  Vanderbilt – Publications – 1971
  Vanderbilt – Publications – 1987
  Receipts – 1970 and 1971
  Distinguished Alumnus Award – October 25, 1996
  Miscellaneous
  - Box 55
  Newspaper Clippings – General Segregation – 1956
  Newspaper Clippings – General Segregation – 1957
  Newspaper Clippings – General Segregation – 1958
  Newspaper clippings – General Segregation – 1961
  Newspaper Clippings – General Segregation – n.d.
  Newspaper Clippings - Church and Segregation – 1956-1957
  Newspaper Clippings – Little Rock – 1957-1958
  Newspaper Clippings – Montgomery Bus Boycott – 1956-1957
  Newspaper Clippings – NAACP – 1957-1958
  Newspaper Clippings – South Africa – 1957-1960
  Newspaper Clippings – General Articles on Churches – 1958-1960
  Newspaper Clippings – General Articles on Communication and Understanding – 1959-1960
  Newspaper Clippings – General Articles on Lunch Counter Strikes – February 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – General Articles on Violence and War – 1958-1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Segregated Facilities – January 1, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Racial Extremism in Harlem – January 25, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Strikes – February 14, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Strikes – February 21, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Strikes – February 28, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Strikes – February 29, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Trials – March 1, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lunch Counter Trials – March 2, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Dismisses Lawson – March 3, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Vanderbilt Dismisses Lawson – March 4, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Protests for Lawson Expulsion – March 5, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 6, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 7, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 8, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 9, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 11, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Lawson Expulsion – March 15, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Racial Bias – March 19, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Ministers Urge Lunch Freedom – March 20, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Dean Criticizes Lawson Ouster – March 22, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Board to Review Lawson Expulsion – March 23, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Board to Review Lawson Expulsion – March 25, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Mass Boycott – March 26, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Sitdowns in the South – March 28, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – VU Defends Lawson Dismissal – March 30, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – VU Faculty and Students resign – March 31, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – General Sit-Ins – April 2, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – NAACP Stands Behind Sit-Ins – April 7, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Sit-Ins Resumed in Uptown Stores – April 11, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – The Non-Violent Way – April 23, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – The “Sit-In” Protest – April 25, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Editorial – May 2, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Bias Talk Cited – May 21, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Divinity Dean, 9 Instructors Resign at Vanderbilt University – May 31, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – United Church Women – June 2, 1960
  Newspaper Clippings – Editorials – December 1, 1960 & March 23, 1961
  Newspaper Clippings – Sit-Ins – n.d.
  - Boston University
  Correspondence – incoming – June 1960
  Correspondence – incoming – July 1960
  Correspondence – incoming – August 1960
  Correspondence – outgoing – August 1960
  Correspondence – incoming – 1968
  Correspondence – incoming – 1969
  Courses – Directed Study in Theological Studies – Summer 1960
  Courses – Inter-Testamental Period – Summer 1960 (2 folders)
  Courses – Ecumenical Message of the New Testament – Summer 1960
  Commencement Program – August 10, 1960
  Grades – Summer 1960
  Pamphlet – Methodism’s Challenge in Race Relations – 1960
  Proposal - n.d.
  Pledge – August 1976
- Federal Prison – Conscientious Objector – Korean War – Box 32
  - Correspondence – incoming – April 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – May 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – July 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – August 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – September 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – October 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – December 1951
  - Correspondence – incoming – January 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – March 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – April 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – May 1952
  - Correspondence – outgoing – May 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – June 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – July 1952
  - Correspondence – incoming – n.d.
  - Correspondence – incoming – U.S. Probation Officer 1952-11953
  - Correspondence – incoming – Selective Service 1954-1956
  - Correspondence – incoming – U.S. Department of Justice 1962
  - Diary – May 1951
  - Diary – August 1951
  - Diary – September 1951
  - Diary – October 1951
  - Diary – November 1951
  - Diary – December 1951
  - Diary – January 1952
  - Lawsuit – U.S.A. versus James Morris Lawson 1951
  - Committee for the Defense of James Lawson 1951-1952
  - Lexington Annual Conference 82nd Session 1951
  - Newspaper Clippings 1951
  - Report for Concern – n.d.
  - Writings and Notes – 1951
  - Writings and Notes – 1952
  - Ashland Prison Intramural Leagues Soft Ball Rules – n.d.
  - Certificate of Parole – May 1952
  - Statement to National Conference – August 1952
  - Articles and Reviews by Others
- Church Affiliations
  - Minister – Turner Chapel Methodist Church - Canton, Ohiio
  Local Preacher’s License – August 5, 1947
  - Minister and Teacher - Hislop College in Nagpur, India – Box 31
  Correspondence – incoming – 1953
  Correspondence – incoming – 1954
  Correspondence – outgoing – 1954
  Correspondence – incoming – 1955
  Correspondence – incoming – 1956
  Correspondence – outgoing – 1956
  Statement of my Conversion to a Christian Pacifist
  Collins Pension Fund for Missionaries
  Clippings on India, 1953-1954
  Health Records, 1954-1956
  Pamphlets
  ▪ Concern, 1952
  ▪ Echo, 1952
  ▪ Methodist Social Creed, 1955
  North India Synodical Board, March 1952
  Indo-African Conference, May 1956
  Goodwill Delegation from Uganda, n.d.
  Report on the Christian Approach to Communism in India
  Notes
  - Pastor - Scott Chapel Methodist Church - Shelbyville, Tennessee – 1960-1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – Appointment – 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – August 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – September 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – October 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – November 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – December 1-15, 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – December 16-31, 1960
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1960
  Correspondence – Incoming – January 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – February 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – March 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – April 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – May 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – June 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – July 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – August 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – September 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – October 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – November 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – December 1961
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1961
  Correspondence – Incoming – January 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – February 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – March 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – April 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – May 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – June 1962
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1962
  Correspondence – n.d.
  Calendars – December 1960 to March 1961
  Engagements – April 7, 1961 – Student Christian Conference
  Engagements – April 11, 1961 – Third Annual Gandhi Memorial Lecture
  Engagements – June 27, 1961 – Hampton Institute Ministers Conference
  Engagements – September 1961 – Missionary Orientation Center
  Engagements – October 28, 1961 – Ground Breaking
  Engagements – January 14, 1962 – National Speaker’s Service
  Immunizations Record – 1961
  Reports, etc. – 1957-1962
  Worship Bulletins – 1960
  Worship Bulletins – 1961
  Worship Bulletins – 1962
  Worship Bulletins – n.d.
  - Pastor - Centenary United Methodist Church - Memphis, Tennessee – 1962-1974
  Correspondence – Incoming - 1962
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1963
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1963
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1964
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1965
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1965
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1966
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1967
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1967
  Correspondence – Incoming – March-June, 1968
  Correspondence – Incoming – July-November, 1968
  Correspondence – Incoming – January-April, 1969
  Correspondence – Incoming – August-December, 1969
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1969
  Correspondence – Incoming – Death of James Lawson’s Mother – April 1969
  Correspondence – Incoming – January-June, 1970
  Correspondence – Incoming – July-December, 1970
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1972
  Correspondence – Incoming – January-June, 1973
  Correspondence – Incoming – July-December, 1973
  Correspondence – Incoming/Outgoing – Congressman George Grider – 1965
  Correspondence – Incoming/Outgoing – Senator Ross Bass – 1964-1965
  Correspondence – Incoming/Outgoing – Al Gore, Sr. – 1963-1967
  Engagements – June 17, 1962 – Tennessee Annual Conference
  Engagements – October 23, 1962 – Duke University
  Engagements – October 31, 1962 – Owen College
  Engagements – November 26, 1962 – Owen College
  Engagements – December 7, 1962 – Conference on Social Action and Concern
  Engagements – August 24, 1963 – Northeast Regional Student Leadership Training Conference
  Engagements – February 7, 1964 – Methodist Student Movement of North Carolina
  Engagements – June 1964 – Tennessee Annual Conference
  Engagements – November 5, 1965 – Lester High School
  Engagements – March 25, 1966 – The Christian Student Reacting in a Changing World
  Engagements – August 28, 1966 – Monroe Street Methodist Church
  Engagements – February 14, 1967 – WDIA Tape on Lent
  Engagements – May 16, 1967 – Tennessee-Kentucky Conference
  Engagements – June 28, 1967 – Wesleyan Service Guild
  Engagements – June 20, 1968 – Missionary Conference
  Engagements – August 29, 1968 – New England Area Pastor’s Assembly
  Engagements – October 1968 – National Committee of Black Churchmen
  Engagements – October 16, 1968 – DePauw University White Awareness Week
  Engagements – January 15, 1969 – NCC General Board
  Engagements – March 27, 1969 – Lay-Clergy Session
  Engagements – April 9, 1969 – Catholic Human Relations Council
  Engagements – April 30, 1969 – Evangelical Theological Seminary
  Engagements – May 11, 1969 – Green Cooperative
  Engagements – August 7, 1969 – Biennial Session of the Connectional Laymen
  Engagements – January 28, 1970 – Violence and Non-Violence
  Engagements – January 29, 1970 – Social Principles Study Commission
  Engagements – February 4, 1970 – Life School of Theology
  Engagements – August 26, 1970 – Convocation of United Methodists for Evangelical Christianity
  Engagements – September 1, 1970 – Syracuse Area Pastors’ School
  Engagements – September 18, 1970 – Black Presbyterian Leadership Conference
  Engagements – October 6, 1970 – High Point College
  Engagements – February 21, 1971 – Duke University
  Engagements – April 4, 1971 –Memorial Services for Dr. Martin Luther King